Profile

I am a **Front-end developer, React Native Engineer and UI/UX Designer**. I build design files using Figma. I have experience working with all major frontend tools including the Jamstack, graphQL and styling libraries i.e Material-UI and Styled components. I have a great foundation and core understanding of JavaScript. I have great working knowledge of React-Native, MongoDB and Firebase.

Employment History

UI/UX Developer, TouchInspiration, Nairobi

September 2021 — April 2022

I Designed based on client requirements, simple and intuitive user interfaces that enable users to achieve their desired goals. I was especially fond of seamless mobile designs.

Among my most memorable moments was where:-

- I Settled any client disputes in a professional and pleasant manner.
- I Worked to ensure a positive and hassle-free user experience.

Consultant Software Engineer, Nairobi

April 2022 — Present

Reading extensively on current technologies in order to advice peers on best practices and technologies to use.

Education

Bsc Computer Science, Egerton University, Nakuru

August 2016 — December 2020

Graduated with High Honors in my bachelors in Computer Science. I learnt alot about the IT industry and its eco-systems and with this knowledge i am ready to change the community using my technology skills.

Complete UI/UX Designer, Zero to Mastery Academy, Nairobi

January 2021 — March 2021

Learnt How to design User Interfaces with Figma. I was able to quickly move from Idea to design. I understood how to put users first while designing so as to bring about a seamless experience in client applications.

Javascript Mastery, Zero to Mastery Academy, Nairobi

April 2021 — June 2021

Learnt advanced patterns in Javascript, how to understand complex syntax and using functional programming to come up with great applications.

References

Details

Nationality

Kenyan

Date / Place of birth

31/01/1998

Westlands, Nairobi

Links

Github

LinkedIn

Website

Skills

Management Skills

Public Speaker

Quality Assuarance

Quick Learner

Front-End Development

UI/UX designer

React-Native Engineer

Hobbies

Playing Chess, Watching Ancient History movies Listening to philosophers of the middle ages listening to podcasts. Writing Stories.

Languages

English

Kiswahili

ROSE MACHARIA from EACC(Ethics and Anti Corruption Comission) 0721345556

ELIZABETH KHAHOYA from HELB(Higher Education Loans Board) 0722959179

ROSE MWAVISWA from Miller and Miller Company 0721276431

Others

My Belief

January 2020 — Present

I believe in Quality software that anyone can read.

I believe that hiring the best software engineer is Key to the future of any tech company.

I believe that working towards a certain goal with fellow team members who inspire you is Key to success.

Extra-curricular activities

Sports

June 2015 — Present

Running, Going for Nature walks,

Playing Football, Cycling and Archery.

Internships

Junior Software Engineer, Ongair, Nairobi

June 2019 — August 2019

under supervision from senior developers, I was able to implement features on an existing system. This was my first time gaining industry level experience and i learnt a lot. I worked with React Js and it was one of the best tools i had ever seen.